

## CONTACT

A. Devlin Booth
Los Angeles, CA 90046
(504) 430-6996
adevlin.booth@gmail.com

## **SKILLS**

HTML, CSS, JAVASCRIPT,
JQUERY, MONGODB, AJAX,
MONGOOSE, NODE.JS, EXPRESS,
REACT, PYTHON, MATERIALIZE,
DJANGO, AMAZON S3 CLOUD
STORAGE, POSTGRESQL,
SOCKET.IO, AFFINITY PHOTO,
AFFINITY DESIGNER, AUTO-CAD,
ADOBE: PHOTOSHOP,
ILLUSTRATOR, INDESIGN, XD

## **LINKS**

github.com/adevlinb

linkedin.com/in/devlin-booth

https://devlin-portfolio. herokuapp.com

# **DEVLIN BOOTH**

## **FULL STACK SOFTWARE DEVELOPER AND DESIGNER**

Expert problem solver and communicator in time sensitive and high-pressure situations where multi-tasking, asking for help, and being self-sufficient become necessary for successful outcomes. Coupled with outside-of-the-box design approaches to implementation of visual, structural, and/or spacial elements in a given problem statement. Experiences that yield a well-rounded individual capable of bringing creativity, courtesy, and efficiency to the work environment.

## **EXPERIENCE**

## SOFTWARE ENGINEERING INSTRUCTIONAL ASSOCIATE

GENERAL ASSEMBLY - REMOTE, 06/2022 - 09/2022

- Administering quizzes, introducing assignments, and facilitating student learning of programming languages, frameworks, databases, development patterns, and deployment all while guiding students through the rigorous transformational journey towards apprenticeship in software development.
- Becoming a better leader through mentoring as I continue to learn through veteran instructors.
- Facilitating a safe, supportive, and energetic community that welcomes the various needs and learning styles
  of students.

#### SOFTWARE ENGINEERING APPRENTICESHIP

GENERAL ASSEMBLY - REMOTE, 12/2021 - 03/2022

420 hour immersive program that includes learning multiple languages, frameworks, libraries, and database types through four projects that executed app planning through wire-framing, erd-diagramming, and (AAU) user-story implementation of features for agile web development practices. Additionally took the role of project manager in group git-hub workflow environment in a team of three.

#### XYLA - nodejs, express, react, mongodb, mongoose, google.books API

Social app for book lovers that allows users to add books to their library, make recommendations, make posts, and comment on other users posts in the "social wall." A personal project for me that I intend to continue developing.

#### TasteBuds - python, django, postgresql, amazonS3

Full CRUD dining events and recipe saving app that allows users to create a profile, join groups, create events, and then recommend their recipes to those events with option to vote on recipes.

## Climate Events - nodejs, express, mongodb, mongoose, googleOAuth

Events logging app and diary that provides weather data based on user provided address. Events accessed via dashboard main page that organizes based on upcoming dates and include a searchable tagging system where user can create, read, update, and delete tags on each event.

#### Mastermind - javascript, html, css

Simplified coding logic to build a digital version of the popular 1970's Mastermind coding game. Using DOM manipulation and "click" event listeners to access elements, update state, and develop winning logic.

## TRAINER / SERVER / SPECIAL EVENTS - HOSPITALITY

AVRA, TAO UPTOWN, DOS CAMINOS 07/2011 - 09/2021

- Communicated with guests to meet their needs and ensure guest experience.
- Presented specials and explained menu to each table.
- Collaborated with teammates and provided support when needed.
- Created visual aid for handling guests' allergies / figuring out what they could have.
- · Collected donations for times when co-workers were in need of support.
- · Proficient in micros touch system.

## **EDUCATION**

## **Certificate, Software Engineering Immersive,** 03/2022

General Assembly - Remote

**Masters Degree, Landscape Architecture,** 06/2011

Louisiana State University

**Bachelors Degree, Urban Planning, 12/2007** 

University of New Orleans